[ ♪♪♪ ]
[SCOOBY MUNCHING]
Eee-Hee-Hee-Hee-Hee!
♪ Scooby-Dooby-Doo
Where are you? ♪
♪ We've got
some work to do now ♪
♪ Scooby-Dooby-Doo
Where are you? ♪
♪ We need some help
from you now ♪
SCOOBY-DOO: Scooby-Dooby-Doo!
[CACKLING]
WOMAN: Let go of me!
Okay, now I really have
a wedgie.
Fred! Velma!
Can you guys hurry it up?
This ghost keeps grabbing--
Please!
Jinkies.
Fred.
Come in, Fred.
Fred!
Can you hear me?
Fredster here, Velms.
Shockingly, Daphne's
been captured again.
That's okay.
When the Luna Ghost
rounds the corner with Daphne,
Shaggy and Scooby
will pop out of the barrel--
Then you'll activate
the conveyor belt,
spilling the oil onto the floor.
[LUNA GHOST GIGGLING]
Just remember
my plan.
SHAGGY: Like,
chill out, Scooby-Doo.
Stop shaking.
SCOOBY-DOO:
Me? That's you.
Right. It's me.
Sorry.
[LUNA GHOST GIGGLING]
[SCOOBY-DOO YELPS]
[CLANG]
Boo.
Aagh!
Scooby-Doo,
what are you doing, man?
Like, this is
no time to...
to...
Oh, boy.
Like, there's a ghost
right behind me, isn't there?
Run!
SCOOBY-DOO: Go away. Go!
SHAGGY: Like, I'm trying, buddy!
SCOOBY-DOO: Try?
Fred, now!
FRED: I got him.
Sorry, Velma.
I know, Fred.
Where's the ghost?
He's right behind me.
Skateboard!
[SHAGGY SCREAMING]
Is he still after us, Scoob?
Banzai!
Zoinks! Grab the hook!
Hold on, Shaggy!
Daphne,
are you okay?
I'm so over
this damsel-in-distress
nonsense.
Where's Shagster?
Like, I'm right here, man.
Me too.
Hey, Scoob, that was fun.
Let's grab
another skateboard
and do it again.
Yeah. Eee-Hee-Hee-Hee!
[TIRES SCREECHING]
[ROCK MUSIC]
There you go.
One for you.
Good-looking guy.
All right, nice to see you.
Thank you so much
for saving the factory.
REPORTER:
Pam, any comments?
This is a victory
for any celebrity
who wants to make
a quality action figure.
What's the secret
of your success?
Teamwork.
I do
a tremendous amount of teamwork,
and...
I always have a plan.
Yeah...my plan.
FRED: I knew from the beginning
there was never a phantom.
The Luna Ghost is, in fact...
Old Man Smithers?
The creepy janitor?
Smithers wanted revenge after
you refused to go out with him.
How could you, Pamela?
I'm a lover-boy
of George Clooney-an
proportions.
REPORTER: Fred, how was
the ghost able to fly?
I can answer that.
Watch.
These balloons fill
with a highly potent
helium synthesis,
giving the Luna Ghost...
his weightless
appearance.
I would have
gotten away with it too,
if it weren't
for you meddling kids
and your dumb dog!
I'll get you for this!
Scooby-Dooby-Doo!
Fred, I can't believe
you took credit
for my plan again.
Some plan.
That ghost pawed me
for an hour and a half.
Daph, it's not our fault
you always get kidnapped.
I do not always get kidnapped.
Can't believe you'd say that.
Oh, please.
You come with
your own ransom note.
Hey, my glasses!
Who's helpless now?
I'm going
to kill you, Daphne!
Whoa! Whoa!
Watch the ascot!
Hey, you guys, look,
I know I'm just the dude
that carries the bags,
but it seems to me we all play
an important part in this group.
I mean,
we're just like
a big, delicious banana split.
Fred, you're the big banana.
Daphne's the pastrami
and gum-flavored ice cream.
And Velma,
you're
the sweet-and-sour mustard sauce
that goes on top.
Mm-mm!
That sounds pretty good,
doesn't it?
You know what, Shaggy?
You've really
put it in perspective for me.
Thanks.
I quit.
No.
No way.
You can't quit.
I was going to quit
in, like, two seconds.
Now everyone will think
I copied off the smart girl.
Now, wait a minute,
wait a minute.
Maybe I quit.
I do.
Yeah, I quit.
I'm out of here.
Good riddance.
Don't--
No. Don't go.
Come on, you guys,
don't do this.
Please don't go.
[WHIMPERS]
Do I quit?
No, Scoob...
friends don't quit.
It looks like
it's you and me for a while.
What now, Shaggy?
I guess we'll all just do
what we do best, Scoob.
[ REGGAE MUSIC PLAYING ]
SHAGGY: This is primo.
Man, talk about toasted.
Man, the only thing
I like better
than an eggplant burger
is a chocolate-covered
eggplant burger.
With hot sauce.
Ra-cha-cha-cha!
Hee-hee-hee!
Yeah, just another beautiful day
in paradise.
[BANGING]
I'm looking for a "Mr. Rogers"
and a "Mr. Doo."
The detectives?
It's probably just somebody
looking for us to solve
some terrifying mystery.
Nobody home!
Quick, Scoob-o, grab the food-o.
Let's scram-o.
I'm looking for a "Mr. Rogers"
and a "Mr. Doo."
Let's go!
I'm sorry, dude.
Look, uh...
I'd love to help you out.
You look like
a really nice guy.
We're not detectives anymore.
I've been sent
by Mr. Emile Mondavarious
to invite you
to his world-famous
amusement park, Spooky Island.
We don't go near places
with "spooky," "haunted,"
"forbidden," or "creepy"
in the name.
Or "hydrocolonic".
Right, but that's
for a different reason, man.
But he'd like you
to solve a mystery.
He'll pay you a fee of $10,000.
It's just,
materialism's
not really our bag, man.
Free airfare.
No, thanks.
Room and board.
And all you can eat.
All you can eat?
Fred?
Velma?
Are you going this way?
Mm-hmm.
How have you...
Been?
Yes.
Great. Great.
I'm on
the lecture circuit
with my new book...
Fred on Fred:
The Many Faces of Me.
Jinkies, that's impressive.
And yourself?
I've been working at NASA,
developing hydropowered
missile defense systems.
But, more importantly,
I'm on a journey
of self-discovery.
NASA?
ANNOUNCER:
Charter service
to Spooky Island
will begin boarding
momentarily.
What do you mean
I can't have
seven carry-on bags?
That's so economy.
Crap.Crap.
Oh, no.
I'm not talking to you guys.
What are you doing here?
Isn't it obvious?
We all received
the same letter
from one Emile Mondavarious,
the reclusive owner
of Spooky Island.
It's not fair.
I was going to
solve the mystery all by myself.
And when you get caught?
I'm a black belt now.
I've transformed my body
into a dangerous weapon.
It's true.
Far out.
I guess we're, like,
all going to Spooky Island, man.
Where's Scooby?
Hello.
They don't allow big dogs
on the plane.
You've got to be kidding.
No one is stupid enough
to believe that.
Who's the ugly old broad?
Say hello to Grandma.
SCOOBY-DOO: Aloha.
Flight 3774 to Spooky Island
now boarding.
I wouldn't have agreed to come
if I knew.
Wait, just think about it
for one minute.
Mystery Inc. reunites.
We'll be a team again,
just like the old days,
so come on, gang,
let's do that thing
where we all put our hands in,
we lift them up,
and we go "Whoo-hoo-hoo!"
Only if Fred and Velma do it.
People are watching, Shag.
Roo-hoo.
Yeah, Scoob, "Roo-hoo."
Come on, buddy.
Now, that is
a beautiful work of art.
Ra-ha.
Would you mind me
taking a seat there next to...
To my grandma.
That's my grandma.
Hi, Grandma.
Like, no.
Thanks.
You're welcome.
Bless you.
I'm sorry. My allergies.
It's usually only dogs
that do it.
Maybe I'd better move.
No, wait.
It's probably
just my grandma's perfume.
Yeah, even I sometimes get
a little allergic, you know.
Oh, jeez.
'Cause I'm pretty sure
Grandma wants to go back
and visit with her pal Velma.
Right, Grandma?
Okay.
Boy, oh, boy,
those sure do look
like Scooby Snacks.
I know they're for dogs,
but they're 100% vegetarian,
and I love them.
Like, me too.
Far out.
I've never met another person
who loves Scooby Snacks.
Me neither.
I'm Mary Jane.
Like, that's my favorite name.
Really?
Yeah.
No way.
Hello.
Grandma?
Velma, it's simple
behavior modification.
To cause a dog
to discontinue
any action,
flick it on the nose.
Observe.
Scoob?
See?
SHAGGY:
Sit, Grandma! Bad Grandma!
Don't eat the kitty!
ANNOUNCER:
Welcome to Spooky Island...
the frightfully popular
spring break spot
for college students.
Catch our
Electrical Torture Parade,
"It's a Dead World After All"
and the world-famous
"Splatterhorn".
Scooby-Doo!
And the rest of Mystery Inc.
It's marvelous to see you!
How fanta--
That's the second time
this week.
Thank goodness.
Sorry, it's a new toy.
I'm just getting up to speed
with it.
Welcome.
Thank goodness.
I was afraid
I'd have to lug those
all the way to the hotel.
That's what
Spooky Island's about,
realizing your worst fears.
I'm Emile Mondavarious,
the owner
of this amusement park.
VELMA:
You seem less...
Spooky.
Than we'd have guessed.
I can be pretty spooky
when called upon.
I can go...
"Rrrowr, rrowr!"
Claws and everything.
You wouldn't want to run into me
in a dark alley.
So you're the one
who brought us here?
No.
What brought you here
was your insatiable appetite
for a juicy mystery.
The truth is,
Mystery Inc. is broken up.
That's the beauty
of broken things.
It can be fixed.
Therein lies
its potential.
And I need you
to fix Spooky Island.
VELMA: What's the problem?
EMILE: I believe
somebody's casting a spell
on the students.
Now, listen and look around.
Notice any difference
between those arriving
and those departing?
DAPHNE:They look like sober,
well-behaved college kids.
EMILE: Precisely.
They didn't before they came.
They've changed.
In other words, a magic spell.
Carol!
Carol, how was the island?
Are you tricking on me?
It's me, Brad.
We've known each other
since we were 3.
Back off my grill, son!
Carol,
what are you doing?
I'm terrified.
The young people
that come off that barge,
the people I love the most,
they're in danger.
I'm going
to solve this one first.
Not before I solve it first.
You'll look like total idiots
when you're captured
and I save you.
Thank you. Marvelous.
Maybe we can celebrate later
by having
a little spookapalooza.
Spookapalooza? Ruh-oh.
So you haven't noticed
anything unusual
since you started working here?
Any weirdos
running around?
Uh...no.
[ CHANTING ]
Welcome, dear victims.
My name is N'Goo Tauna.
This is
my evil best pal, Zarkos.
You may recognize him
from
Telemundo
as the famous masked wrestler...
Zarkos.
This enchanted island
is a thoroughfare
to the supernatural realm.
For centuries,
it was home to creatures
who lived on the island,
undisturbed.
But then, 10 years ago,
Emile Mondavarious
antagonized these ancient beings
by building a theme park here.
The creatures are furious,
my friends,
and I assure you
while you party...
they plot their revenge!
Do my friends
frighten you?
They would,
if it weren't for
the holographic projectors
there, and there,
and there.
What a smart
little one.
[TELEPHONE RINGING]
Hello.
Dead Mike's.
We got a "Mr. Doo" here?
I got a call for a "Mr. Doo."
Melvin Doo?
No. Scooby.
Hello?
MAN:
Got a bag
of hamburgers for you.
Just walk into the dark,
shadowy part of the forest
where no one
can see you.
Okay.
SHAGGY: Want a stuffed thingy?
Nobody can win those.
Fred says
it's a worthless talent,
that I should've
learned French instead.
I say you don't
need to know
what
"Voulez-vous
coucher avec moi"
means
to love that song.
I think being good
at crane machine
is way cooler
than French.
Voilà!
Nobody's ever given me
a stuffed dismembered head
before.
Excuse me.
Now I have to start
my voodoo ritual all over again!
Voodoo ritual?
I was about to sacrifice
this chicken.
That chicken's not alive.
I know it's not alive,
little girl.
Did you figure that out
when you didn't see its head?
No.
Why you all up
in the voodoo ritual space?
I'm looking for clues
as to who's behind
the students'
strange behavior.
Well, here's a clue:
Purple is a fall color.
It's the middle of May!
Pardon?
Get off this island.
Go home.
Go home before evil befalls
your skinny, aerobicized booty.
And whatever you do,
do not,
I repeat, do not go into
that Spooky Island castle.
Ah-hah!
You want me
to go to that castle.
Didn't you hear what I said?
But you're scary.
You knew I'd do
the opposite of what you said.
You told me
not to go to the castle
so I would go to the castle,
where you set a trap
to capture me...
unless...
you knew I'd figure it out,
so you told me not to go
so I'd think
you wanted me to go,
so I wouldn't go.
Huh?
I'll find out what you're hiding
in that castle.
You watch.
What in the world?
Hamburgers...
where are you?
Hamburgers. Oh, boy.
Hamburgers.
Thank you.
Shaggy!
It's been really nice.
Monster! Monster!
A monster?
Scooby-Doo,
quit goofing around, man.
I guess I should go.
Bye, Scooby.
Bless you.
Shaggy. Scooby.
No way.
Shaggy...
Scoob and me
don't do castles.
Why not?
They have paintings
with eyes that watch you
and suits of armor
you think is a statue
but there's a guy inside
who follows you
every time you turn around.
How many times did that happen?
12. We're not going to do it.
That's right.
Scooby?
Did you hurt
your paw?
Would you do it
for a Scooby Snack?
Oh, boy!
And you'll be fearless?
Fearless?
Hong Kong Phooey,
watch the fists of fury.
Here you go.
Thank you.
There's plenty more
where that came from.
Let's go before someone sees.
You're not going to
stay out here alone, are you?
No thank you.
Oh, boy.
This place is, like,
uber
creepy.
Yeah,
uber
creepy.
The only thing missing
is a mindless zombie.
Fred, get back.
I found this place.
I call dibs on its clues.
I've already found some clues.
What?
I followed
some weird footprints here.
It might be dangerous for you.
If anyone messes with me,
I'll open
a can of Chinese whoop-ass.
Velma!
What are you doing here?
This ride was closed
for construction.
It's the most likely place
to hatch a plan.
And I wanted
to scare Daphne.
Since we're all together,
let's split up
and look for more clues.
Daphne, you and I--
Typical.
What?
Oh, nothing.
I was always picked last
for the teams.
Okay.
Daphne,
exit through the entrance.
Velma and I
will enter through the exit.
And Shaggy and Scooby...
do whatever you guys do.
Wow...
Look at this, huh, Scoob?
It's like a medieval
Sizzler.
Pinch me, I'm in heaven--
Ow. It's an expression, Scoob.
Sorry.
Velma, I never meant to--
Well, you know,
pick you last.
Don't worry about it, Fred.
I know you.
All you care about
are swimsuit models.
No!
Look, I'm a man
of substance.
Dorky chicks like you
turn me on too.
That's a compliment.
Yes! Yes!
Oh, yeah. Oh, yeah.
Oh, yeah. Oh, yeah. Oh, no!
CREEPY VOICE:
And now for our dinner show.
Watch out!
I've got
a bad feeling about this.
Me too.
And now for the main course...
you!
[EVIL LAUGHTER]
Feast on this.
Jinkies.
They're moving
toward us.
Run!
We're trapped.
Quick, try the bookcase.
One of these
has to open a secret passageway.
Velma, this is a ride.
You got a better plan, Fred?
What do we do?
Do what we do best, Scoob--
eat.
It's plastic.
So what?
You drink out of a toilet.
So do you.
I'm not helpless.
I am helpless.
I'm going to die!
We made it, Scoob. We're alive!
That was weird.
Fred?
Freddy?
Are you all right?
The last book.
I don't feel so good.
Reminds me of the time
we tried to eat
that guy in the hot-dog costume.
Looks like
some kind of school.
In a spooky
castle ride?
Fishy.
Welcome to America.
I am using the language
English.
Shaggy, look.
Let's check it out.
Oh, boy.
Lights, camera, action,
huh, Scoob?
Now that you're a young adult,
you'll need to learn
societal do's...
and don'ts.
Interaction
between young people
is polite and casual.
Hey, sorry, bro.
I will crush your bones
into dust.
Let's see how the situation
should be handled.
Remember, today's young people
have a language all their own.
Sorry, bro.
No big whoop, dog.
Catch that new vid on the box?
True dat.
I'm up to sniznuff
on all popular trends.
Word.
It seems to be
a brainwashing facility
of some type.
Wherever
there's a brainwashing cult,
there's always
a power-hungry leader.
The Papa Smurf figure.
Mondavarious.
Mm...
Then why would he have
invited us here?
Jellybeans.
[BELCHES]
I'll have whatever he's having.
Are you challenging me?
Maybe.
[BELCHES]
[BREAKS WIND]
Pull my finger.
Uh-uh. Too late.
[BELCHES]
You're in trouble.
Oh, boy.
[BREAKS WIND]
[SHAGGY AND SCOOBY-DOO
BREAKING WIND]
I'm not stopping
till your fur's singed off.
We're here to solve a mystery.
Yeah, Scoob.
[ALARM SOUNDING]
Let's get out of here.
Zoinks! Skedaddle!
I found
a neat and scary clue.
Us too.
This is a brainwashing facility
for an evil cult.
Maybe this is
the secret relic thingy
they worship.
We'll all be relics
if we don't get out of here.
I've got a plan.
What's that smell?
Sir, they found
the Daemon Ritus.
They better not have gone far.
[CRASHING]
It is time
to summon the big muchachos.
SHAGGY:
Like, oh, no!
[BREAKING WIND]
Ah, Mystery Inc.
You all seem rather cheery.
Good news, I hope?
Mr. Mononucleosis....
Yes?
We have hit a clue smorgasbord.
We have three suspects
as to who's behind
this evil hooty.
N'Goo Tauna.
He believes
your park's on enchanted ground.
DAPHNE: The voodoo man,
who tricked me
into going to the castle.
And you.
Me?
FRED: Let's split up.
I'll interview employees
to see if they've noticed
anything odd.
I'll translate
these inscriptions
Daphne found.
I'll go research cults
on the Net.
I'm a suspect?
Don't take it personally.
It's because you creep me out.
I see.
Fine.
Jinkies.
[PLAYING PIANO]
Hey. Your friends
ditch you?
No, I always did
the brainwork.
What's this?
I believe it's called
the Daemon Ritus.
Daemon Ritus?
What's it for?
This describes
an old race of creatures.
It's reminiscent
of Pandaemonous texts,
so I can make some of it out.
It looks like instructions
to some sort of secret ritual.
It is fascinating.
WAITER:
On the house.
Nice sweater.
You really dig
doing this, huh?
Like, clues and stuff.
Certainly.
Really focusing on a mystery
reminds me of the old days.
We were quite a crew back then.
That was
the best time of my life.
Shaggy and Scooby.
What goofballs!
Kind of like they are today.
And Daphne....
So beautiful.
She was the coolest girl
at Coolsville High.
Fred. He was so handsome.
And he really knew
how to accessorize.
Sounds perfect.
Yeah, but every family
has one nut.
Scrappy-Dappy-Doo!
Ghosts don't stand a chance
with me.
Let me at 'em.
I'll rock 'em. I'll sock 'em.
For the 1000th time,
there's no such thing as ghosts.
Sure there are.
When I find them,
I'll give them a dose
of puppy power!
Oh, God. He's peeing on me.
[BRAKES SCREECHING]
VELMA:
That little egomaniac
had flipped his lid.
Scrappy, I told you,
no urinating on Daphne.
It was an accident.
You were marking
your territory.
You don't have the scrote
for this job.
Listen up, losers.
The time has come to appoint me
your unquestioned leader.
Either that, or I'm out of here.
What's the idea?
You can't do this to me.
People adore me.
Ow!
I'm as cute as a Powerpuff Girl.
I'll get my own show.
Puppy power, huh?
And he wasn't even a puppy.
He had a gland disorder.
Help me! Help me!
Monsters! Monsters!
This is the most
embarrassing thing you've done
since you cleaned your beans
at Don Knotts' Christmas party.
Hee-hee-hee-hee!
How many times
do I have to tell you?
There are no such things
as ghouls,
ghosts, goblins, or monsters.
Now listen up.
There is absolutely--
absolutely no such thing as--
Monster!
Fred!
FRED: Scooby....
Save Daphne.
My glasses.
I can't find my glasses.
Help me find my glasses.
Here they are.
Thank you.
Nice mask.
Bad breath.
Jinkies.
Velma!
Come on!
This is, like, the opposite
of what I wanted to do today.
Leave it!
Stand back, sir.
I'll protect you.
Mr. Mondavarious!
Daphne, go!
Scooby-Doo, where are you?
Run, suitcase.
Run, suitcase. Run--
Thank you.
Where's Scooby?
I hope he's okay.
I'm here!
Scooby-Dooby-Doo!
Scooby!
[ GRUMBLING ]
[ ROARING ]
I have
a sinking feeling
these dudes aren't
brainwashed cult members.
What do they want
with the students?
We need to follow them.
Say what?
Defeat them
and save Fred and Velma.
Sort of like my plan--
get out of here
and let the creatures
eat Fred and Velma.
No way.
Fred and Velma
always figured out everything.
Now it's our turn.
For the first time,
they're the damsels in distress,
not me.
Help?
Timber.
Okay, I'm calling
for help.
No. I got this.
I got this.
I don't got this.
[TELEPHONE RINGING]
Coast Guard, Fitzgibbon.
Hello, sir.
We're on Spooky Island.
Our friends were...
kidnapped.
We need someone here
right away.
We do have a unit
in the vicinity.
Can you meet them at the pier?
All right,
they'll be right there.
"Our friends
have been kidnapped."
Something messed up
is happening.
Is the Coast Guard here?
What happened
to the shattered windows
and busted walls?
Yo, red. The ball?
Let's go.
Anyone else
think this is strange?
Okay, we need
to split up.
Why?
We need to find
Fred and Velma.
I'll go this way.
And we'll go with you.
Come on, Scoob.
♪ ...Baby ♪
♪ I count the days
till I see you again ♪
♪ I'm sorry ♪
♪ One night
can make a difference ♪
♪ Please don't leave me
hanging on and on ♪
♪ I see the light
in your window... ♪
Fred?
Yo, the bitch was like, "What?"
And I was like, "Later on!"
What up, dog?
And...
dog.
Keeping it real.
What happened last night?
We got beats
like it was the lizz-nizz.
You know what
I'm saying, G?
No.
[CRASHING]
You hear that?
Get the dog.
Aha! Damsel in distress.
Let go of me. Help!
Hurry, get the door!
Why is Fred in a bad mood?
He's not in a bad mood, Scoob.
He's a monster.
Shaggy, bikes!
I know, "yikes!"
No, bikes!
Scoob!
Yahoo!
Shaggy, look out!
Something's wrong
with my friend, Beth Ann!
Like, hop on!
Like, what a drag!
Like, duck!
Yes!
That was great!
Are you all right?
You were great.
You too.
Scooby-Doo, what are you doing?
Mary Jane
is a man in a mask.
Mary Jane is a man in a mask?
Scooby...
What are you doing, man?
Step off, Scoob.
Shaggy, you're whipped.
I'm whipped? Yeah?
Why don't you say that
to my face?
Okay, I will.
Your mommy eats cat poop!
No, Scooby-Doo,
your mom eats cat poop!
Bring it.
You want a piece
of the Shagster?
Feel the pain, Scoob.
Come on! Two shots! Two shots!
Me and you, me and you again.
Scoob!
Scooby's been eaten.
I've got to save him.
You stay here,
I'll be right back!
[IN A MAN'S VOICE]
No, Shaggy.
[IN A WOMAN'S VOICE]
I mean, it's too dangerous.
I've got to.
He's, like, my best pal.
Friends don't quit.
Scoob?
Scooby-Doo...
where are you?
WOMAN: Shaggy.
Shaggy.
Shaggy!
Velma.
I'll save you.
Thanks, Shaggy.
Boy, am I glad
to see you.
Let me go
so I can return
to my body,
and then get out of here
before they find you
and steal
your protoplasm too.
I always knew you were a hero,
Shaggy.
Jinkies!
Hey, buddy.
Shaggy!
Someone must have spiked
my root beer last night.
Talk me down, man.
Talk me down.
Fred, you're a frigging
protoplasmic head.
I know,
but I'm still the best-looking
protoplasmic head here.
How do you
drive this thing?
The Darkopalypse
is upon us.
Get what you need
for the ceremony.
On your right.
Your left.
I'm coming, good-looking!
Thank you so much.
You've saved me.
Sorry.
I'm looking for my friends.
But--
Put me back, Shaggy.
I'll figure a way out myself.
Like, how?
I'll use my tongue as an oar
and swim to the edge.
Sorry.
Yo, yo, you, yo.
What the--
You could use a little sunlight.
That's one part
of the mystery solved.
The creatures need our bodies
to survive in sunlight.
Like a human suit.
SPF 1,000,000.
But what are
they doing here
in the first place?
Daphne, you okay?
[IN A MAN'S VOICE]
Yeah.
But I'm not Daphne!
Fred?
I couldn't get to my body.
I didn't know where else to go.
It's not easy to steer
when you're pure spirit.
I can look at myself naked.
Oh, brother.
DAPHNE'S VOICE:
Get your hands off me.
Daphne?
He planned this
somehow, didn't he?
Hey, good-looking.
Fred, you egocentric--
Please tell me
you guys are you.
Fred keeps touching me.
Kind of makes you nostalgic
for the homicidal creatures.
I stole this.
I hope it helps.
The Daemon Ritus.
Hey, I'm me again.
[AS VELMA]
Yippee for you.
[AS SHAGGY]
Why am I wearing a dress?
[AS FRED] Everyone remain calm.
Velma, what the heck's going on?
[AS VELMA] If I am correct,
due to the instability
of protoplasm
in the proximity
of the Daemon Ritus,
we're going to continue
randomly changing bodies until--
[AS VELMA] Until the protoplasm
realigns with the right bodies.
[AS DAPHNE] I'm Fred again!
[AS SHAGGY]
Daph, what's wrong with you?
Don't you ever eat?
I'm me.
DAPHNE: I'm back.
Like, me too.
Told you so.
[EXPLOSION]
Oh, no.
Let's go.
Something tells me
that was the wrong ingredient.
Wait.
I know
how to handle this guy.
Hey, you! What're you doing?
Yes. That is
masterful.
I'm trying to do a voodoo
ritual, if you don't mind.
It's important to get
the right ingredients.
The only way I can
protect myself
is by blessing
this dead Arnouki beast.
They're about to perform
their evil Darkopalypse ritual.
Darkopalypse ritual?
That's right.
That's what
the ancient text describes.
Don't open that!
They use the protoplasm
as an energy source.
And the leader needs to absorb
a purely good soul
to complete the ritual.
Legend has it,
once the ritual is performed,
the creatures
will rule on Earth
for 10,000 years.
That's why
I have this in my house.
To protect myself.
You have another one of those?
DAPHNE: Those creatures
are taking over the world?
That is so mean!
They can't do it
without a pure human soul.
Where will they get one?
I didn't say human.
Oh, boy.
[WHIMPERS]
Hello, puppy.
If the person behind all this
needs Scooby-Doo....
Then that person is the one
who brought Scooby here.
Scoobert!
How are you, my friend?
Sit down, please.
Okay.
Scooby Snack?
Maybe one.
We'll need
some more of those.
That's me!
It certainly is.
And that's because...why?
We love you, Scooby-Doo.
Unlike that
alleged friend of yours, Shaggy.
He wouldn't believe you
about that nasty girl,
Mary Jane,
would he?
No.
But I believe you,
my friend.
And that's why I've got
a very important job
for you.
What's that?
That's a cat
with a bobbing head.
Please don't touch it.
Scooby, I would like you...
to be a sacrifice.
A sacrifice?
If Mondorajagaga
wanted Scooby,
why'd he invite us?
It doesn't matter.
We've got to go save Scoob.
Our area of expertise
is nut jobs
in Halloween costumes.
We're supposed to be heroes.
So I'm going to do
what I always do.
I'm going to eat myself
a Scooby Snack,
and I'm going to save
my best pal.
FRED: Velmster?
You think
I'm going to fall for that?
Giving me my own nickname?
Trying to make me feel
like part of the gang?
We could make a plan.
What can I do?
The only thing I'm good for
is getting caught.
But you never let that
stop you before.
And if that's not a true hero,
then I don't know what is.
Let's get jinkie with it.
Okay, so we use the pulleys
to tip over the vat.
VELMA:
Daphne will open the air vents
and release the disco skull.
The light will refract off it--
The creatures will explode,
I'll find Scoob,
and we'll have saved the world!
FRED:
Oh, no. The ritual's beginning.
Quick!
Attach this to the vat!
We're here to save you!
VELMA:
Shaggy, faster.
All systems go!
Wait, no!
Mystery Inc. rides again.
Quick! Hide the Daemon Ritus!
Would you like
another Scooby Snack?
Okay.
Scooby-Doo!
♪ This is
what we creatures sing ♪
Yo, yo, yo. Yo, homedogs!
Y'all forgot
the next part of the dance,
where we do
the electric slide, you know?
♪ And back it on up
and drive the bus ♪
♪ Drive the bus and stop ♪
♪ And back it up... ♪♪
Hurry up, Velma.
Welcome to my little
end-of-the-world party.
I've waited a long time
for this moment.
Thank you for returning
the ultimate party favor:
The Daemon Ritus.
And now, behold the sacrifice.
Thank you. Thank you.
Hello. Thank you.
Thank you. Shaggy?
Let's run for it.
We've got to
get out of here.
I'm a sacrifice.
A sacrifice?
Dude,
that's not a good thing, Scoob.
I'm sorry I yelled at you.
And I'm sorry
I haven't been
a very good friend
since we got here.
But you've got to trust me now.
You don't trust me!
I do trust you.
Now, look.
Who's your best buddy?
Shaggy.
And who's my best buddy?
Scooby-Doo?
That's right, Scoob.
You are.
And we're like two trippy peas
in a far-out pod, man!
Best buddies trust each other.
Let's do what we do best.
Let's run out of here
screaming in fear
like two lunatics, okay?
Okay!
On the count of--
Let's make it five.
One.
Two.
Scooby-Doo!
[GIGGLING]
Hey, look at me!
[ YELPS ]
EMILE: The moment is at hand.
Through the Daemon Ritus,
I shall absorb
the energy source.
And now to complete
the transformation,
I shall absorb the pure one!
Scoob!
Ultimate power shall be mine!
Nobody absorbs my pal!
Come on!
SCOOBY-DOO: I'm free!
Look at me!
Get him!
Come on, let's get
the Daemon Ritus!
Get off my pincer!
Cowabunga!
Hey! Look, Velms.
A man in a mask.
EMILE:
We love you, Scooby-Doo.
We love you.
That alleged friend of yours,
Shaggy.
I shall absorb...
Puppy power!
I've outsmarted--
Scrappy-Doo.
Correction.
The new, improved Scrappy!
Because I, Scrappy-Dappy-Doo,
have absorbed enough energy
to rule the world
with my all-powerful army!
And I've brought you here,
puny, pathetic Mystery Inc.,
to witness my moment of triumph.
All I need
to complete my transformation
is Scooby-Doo.
Me? Don't you mean Melvin Doo?
Seize them!
Like, let's get out of here!
Take that, pretty boy!
This is totally
ungroovy, Scoob!
Scooby-Doo, where are you?
Señorita...
♪ Scooby-Dooby-Doo
Where are you? ♪
♪ We've got
some work to do now ♪
We've got to tip over
the protoplasm vat.
The pincer. Come on!
You all need
to step back,
because Fredster's
got his groove on.
Got you!
You look so much bigger on TV!
Shaggy!
Scoob!
Come back here,
you lazy beatnik!
Crud!
Told you so!
Like, wow!
[AS A MAN]
Give me the dog!
Scrappy, down!
Sit! Bad Scrappy!
Let's finish this puppy! Now!
Not again!
Captured again,
señorita?
Not this time!
Now who's
the damsel in distress?
Me?
Straight up.
Mystery Inc., this ain't over!
Not by a long shot!
I'll rock you and sock you
and crush you like--
Like, dude.
What?
You're a bad puppy!
Come on, I can still take you!
Put them up, you mangy mutt!
Is that all you got?
Hey, Daph!
We did it!
Yes, we did.
Fred,
cut it out!
[BANGING]
Mr. Mondavarious,
is that you?
Oh, thank goodness!
Thank you! Thank you!
Velma! Thank you!
You're fogging up my glasses.
Two years ago,
that little pest
turns up at a casting session
for our evil elves.
Next thing I know,
I'm stuck in a hole
and he's cavorting about
in a mechanical version of me.
But look, thank you so much!
What a delight! Fantastic!
Fantastic!
Shaggy!
Scooby-Doo!
I love you, Shaggy.
I love you, too, Scoob.
Now, get off me, buddy.
Hey.
Thanks.
You saved my life.
Like, no problem.
Uh-oh.
And thank you, Scooby-Doo.
My little
schmookem-wookem.
Shucks.
[ CHEERING ]
Fred, can you tell us
how you solved the case?
It all started
when I was giving a speech
on my new book and...
And...
I think the Velmster
should take it from here.
Through the combined
intuitive powers
of Mystery Inc.,
we've discovered
the real villain is, in fact,
Scrappy Cornelius Doo,
who sadly was corrupted
by the Daemon Ritus.
SCRAPPY:
Oh, get over it!
So I got a little cranky.
It's no reason
to freak out like a jerk
and try to kill
all humanity.
I would've gotten away with it
if not
for you meddling sons of--
Now that Mystery Inc.
is back together,
any comment
on the Mud Bog Ghoul
terrorizing London?
Whatever the case,
Mystery Inc.
will be there.
Solving mysteries, man.
Righting wrongs.
Looking for clues
and kicking butt.
How groovy is this, man?
Spooky Island
finally came through
with its all-you-can-eat deal.
And there's nobody
I'd rather gorge myself with
than you, Scooby-Doo.
My best friend.
You're my best friend, buddy.
You're beautiful
like a beautiful piece of pizza.
Zoinks!
Them peppers is, like, hot.
Wimp.
Wimp? You think
you can handle it?
Why don't you
put your mouth
where your mouth is?
Okay.
Scooby-Doo,
you feeling okay?
Here you go, dude.
Like, how'd
that taste, man?
Delicious.
Well, let's get two more.
On the count of three.
One, two...three!
[SCREAMING]
♪ Ruff to my left
Ruff to my right ♪
♪ You never knew a dog
And a mic would sound so tight ♪
♪ Ruff to my left
Ruff to my right ♪
♪ Gimmie Scooby Snacks and
I'll be rapping all night ♪
♪ Bow-wow-wow
Scooby yo and Scooby say ♪
♪ You know that Scoob and Shaggy
In the house ♪
♪ Bow-wow-wow
Scooby yo and Scooby say ♪
♪ You know that Scoob and Shaggy
In the house ♪
♪ In the Van of Mystery
Making doggy history ♪
♪ Rolling drop the twenties ♪
♪ So you better not
Be dissin' me ♪
♪ Got a blinged out collar
And an iced out chain ♪
♪ When I'm rolling
Down the block ♪
♪ You'll say my name ♪
♪ Scooby Doo ya'll
Scooby Dooby Doo ya'll ♪
Scooby Dooby Doo ♪
♪ Check 1-2, 1-2
Up on my Scooby mic ♪
♪ You never knew a dog
And a mic would sound so tight ♪
♪ Ruff to my left
Ruff to my right ♪
♪ You never knew a dog
And a mic would sound so tight ♪
♪ Ruff to my left
Ruff to my right ♪
♪ Gimmie Scooby snacks
And I'll be rapping all night ♪
♪ Light on my paws
Stacks in my drawers ♪
♪ In my contract
Is a no cats clause ♪
♪ Breakin' out of pounds
Runnin' out of bounds ♪
♪ Hypnotizing Ma's
With the Scooby, Scooby, sound ♪
♪ Scooby is the dog
That saves me ♪
♪ Scooby snacks are the way
That he pays me ♪
♪ These crooks are just so crazy
And Shaggy is so, so lazy ♪
♪ A diggy-dog ya'll
He won't fall ya'll ♪
♪ And with his main man Shaggy
Standing tall, ya'll ♪
♪ And give a Scooby call ya'll
Have a ball ya'll ♪
♪ Never fall ya'll
He's in it for the long haul ♪
♪ Long haul ♪
♪ Ha, ha, ha, Scooba-dee-doo ♪
♪ Scooby Doo, where are you? ♪
♪ Ruff to my left
Ruff to my right ♪
♪ You never knew a dog
And a mic would sound so tight ♪
♪ Ruff to my left
Ruff to my right ♪
♪ Gimmie Scooby snacks
And I'll be rapping all night ♪♪
♪ In the land
Of a million drums ♪
♪ There is
Always something going ♪
♪ On, on, on, on ♪
♪ If you can't locate
Your thought off might as well ♪
♪ Go on take your dead
Home, home, home, home ♪
♪ In the land
Of a million drums ♪
♪ I catch a pattern that spit
Rings around it like Saturn ♪
♪ Intergalatic tracks
I make 'em like magstrulium ♪
♪ This one for Scooby
Pass the doobie ♪
♪ I'm a do me one, do we run ♪
♪ Only you clean over
I pick up the mic and rock it ♪
♪ While I'm sober
For the rated G exposure ♪
♪ If you listen what I'm tryin
To told ya we fathers
♪ With seeds of our own we talk
About sons and daughters ♪
♪ Not roots and clones now that
The theory gone wrong ♪
♪ An embryo with no soul Stuck
In this green mini-van
♪ With my lungs
In a chokehold ♪
♪ Shaggy pass the boombastic
Daphne said don't do that ♪
♪ Freaky Fred smashed the gas
And slammed us into traffic ♪
♪ Now Scrappy wanna box
And throw them bowls ♪
♪ So I had to sic the pitbull
On him before ♪
♪ He could pass one blow
Scooby-doo, Scooby-doo ♪
♪ Scooby Doo, Scooby Doo ♪
♪ Scooby-Dooby-Doo! ♪
♪ In the land
of a million drums ♪
♪ There is
Always something going ♪
♪ On, on, on, on ♪
♪ If you can't locate
Your thought off might as well ♪
♪ Go on take your dead
Home, home, home, home ♪
♪ Woke up from a long night
Of hanging out with Shaggy ♪
♪ Oh no, lost my last baggy
Of Scoobie Snackies ♪
♪ Shaggy wake up
We've been had ♪
♪ Our scooby snacks
They got the whole stash ♪
♪ He said, "Who? Who?"
I don't have a clue ♪
♪ I suspect the 13 ghosts
of Scoobie Doo ♪
♪ Call Vincent Price
up on the Nextel ♪
♪ Tell him to send another
Package right through the mail ♪
♪ In the meantime
I'm a call Thelma to tell her ♪
♪ To get the Mystery Machine
ready I'm two-wayin' ♪
♪ Daphne and Freddy me and
Shaggy dressed in all black ♪
♪ Strapped dippin' through
the flash tryin'
♪ To get our stash back
Roundin' up suspects ♪
♪ Collectin' clues
I got a question ♪
♪ Where the hell is Scooby Doo
When you need 'em? ♪
♪ The hound's only found
When you feed him ♪
♪ In fact he probably
Got my sack ♪
♪ Tell him holler back ♪
♪ In the land
of a million drums ♪
♪ There is
Always something going ♪
♪ On, on, on, on ♪
♪ Break it down
Break it down Baby
♪ Till the flow jumps
Off the ground ♪
♪ Ooh, break it down
Lookin' over yonder ♪
♪ Till the walls
Come tumblin' down ♪
♪ Ooh, yes, lord you
Ain't gotta tell me ♪
♪ Two times
But you know I know ♪
♪ Ooh, break it down
Break it down baby ♪
♪ 'Cause I want y'all all
To know we rock the world ♪
♪ In the land
of a million drums ♪
♪ There is
Always something going ♪
♪ On, on, on, on ♪
♪ I woulda got away
With it ♪
♪ If it wasn't
For ya meddlin' kids ♪
♪ Oh oh, oh no ♪
♪ I woulda got away
With it ♪
♪ If it wasn't
For ya meddlin' kids ♪
♪ Oh oh, oh no ♪
♪ I woulda got away
With it ♪
♪ If it wasn't
For ya meddlin' kids ♪
♪ Oh oh, oh no ♪♪